Hallelujah!
Turn to your neighbour and greet them, "Emmanuel".
Emmanuel!
(God With Us – Matthew 1:23)
Give your neighbour a handshake and say, "Emmanuel".
Give your other neighbour a handshake and say, "Emmanuel".
Give your neighbour behind you a handshake and say, "Emmanuel".
Give your neighbour in front of you a handshake and say, "Emmanuel".
Greet the viewers all over the world on Emmanuel TV, "Emmanuel!"
God is with us.
Whilst we are still standing, please join me and thank God for the life of Prophet T.B. Joshua.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
There are no words that can describe what God has used Prophet T.B. Joshua
not only to do in my life but to do in this generation.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Blessed are our eyes for seeing what we have seen
and blessed are our ears for hearing what we have heard.
A prophet is in our midst.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Right now, you may have your seats, in the presence of God, and say, "Thank You, Jesus".
My name is Chris,
and by the special grace of God, I have the opportunity today to share with you
the sweet story of our Lord, Jesus Christ.
It is the greatest privilege on earth to be able to share the Gospel of Jesus Christ
to all of you and all the viewers on Emmanuel TV.
Last week, we received a very wonderful message from Prophet T.B. Joshua
which was titled, ‘The Greatest Achievement On Earth’.
Now, who can remind me: What is the greatest achievement on earth?
I hope you have been watching the sermon on Emmanuel TV.
What is the greatest achievement on earth?
If someone can remind me of what Prophet T.B. Joshua said last week?
Remember; it is not in terms of material possessions, wealth, position - no.
What is the greatest achievement here on earth?
Can anyone remind me?
OK.
Good morning, Church.
Last week we heard that the greatest achievement on earth is to pray as God wants us to pray.
Amen.
Amen; let's put our hands together for our sister.
Yes, that is the greatest achievement on earth.
We are not just talking about the prayer of the lips.
We are talking about the prayer of the heart
because the heart of prayer is prayer from the heart.
Tell your neighbour, "Neighbour, the heart of prayer is prayer from the heart".
We are going to talk about the heart today – the ‘man himself’.
Tell you neighbour, "The man himself".
That is the real you, the true you – the heart.
We are going to talk about the need for us to take care of our hearts.
Tell your neighbour, "Take care of your heart".
We know, as 1 Thessalonians 5:23 says that
man is a divine being possessed of spirit, soul and body.
In other words, you are a spirit living in the physical body, learning to live in the natural world.
Tell your neighbour, "I am a spirit".
The real thing about you is your spirit, is your heart.
That is the real thing about you.
That is the communication point for God, the contact point, the landing point,
the strong room, the powerhouse – the heart.
Tell your neighbour, “Take care of your heart”.
We also read in John 4:24 that
God Himself is Spirit and those who worship Him must do so in Spirit and in truth.
What does this mean?
If we do not worship God who is a Spirit, in the Spirit, we miss the end of worship.
We miss the point.
If it is not in Spirit, it is not in truth and so it is all nothing – in vain.
This is what happens when your church service turns into a ceremony.
You know the time the service begins, you know the time the service ends,
you know the pre-planned program for the day, who will preach the title of the sermon for the next four weeks,
because the Holy Spirit is not the one releasing the words.
If the Holy Spirit does not release the words,
you may speak the truth but you are just speaking today’s language.
That truth cannot penetrate the hearts.
It can strike the ear, but not ring in the conscience.
Until today’s church realises that the spirit of man, the heart of man
is the fountain of faith, only then will the Holy Spirit begin to be involved in our affairs.
God is Spirit; you too are spirit.
The Word of God is Spirit.
So for you to have a relationship with Him, it must be in the Spirit, in the heart.
Tell your neighbour, “Take care of your heart”.
Let's turn to our proof text for today's message, which is the Book of Matthew 23.
I will read from verse 1; the main text we will be going to is from verses 25-27.
So, verse 1:
“Then Jesus said to the crowds and to His disciples:
‘The teachers of the law and the Pharisees sit in Moses’ seat.
So you must be careful to do everything they tell you.
But do not do what they do, for they do not practice what they preach.’”
Now, let's move to verse 25.
Remember, this is our Lord, Jesus Christ speaking to His people.
Verse 25:
“’Woe to you, teachers of the law and Pharisees, you hypocrites!
You clean the outside of the cup and dish, but inside they are full of greed and self-indulgence.
Blind Pharisee! First clean the inside of the cup and dish, and then the outside will also be clean.'"
Verse 27:
“’Woe to you, teachers of the law and Pharisees, you hypocrites!
You are like whitewashed tombs, which look beautiful on the outside
but on the inside are full of the bones of the dead and everything unclean.’”
Tell your neighbour, "Neighbour, take care of your heart".
Jesus was describing a situation where someone cares for their flesh,
their appearance, their external and neglect their heart -
the real you, the true you – the ‘man himself’.
Now, I want to try to use an example, based on the Scripture that may relate to us in a more clear-cut way.
Just imagine; you have had a long day at work, you have worked hard, tirelessly,
and you are coming home to eat, and you know that your favourite food has been prepared.
And when you get back to your home, you see the food prepared...
You are tired, stressed, you have had a long day, you are hungry and you see a beautiful plate of food,
beautifully presented, looking wonderful, beautifully prepared.
Let me just ask someone.
Sir, what is your favourite food?
Pap & rice.
Pap & rice - let's clap for our brother.
I think that's South African, right?
Wonderful - pap & rice.
Just imagine; you have a beautiful dish of pap & rice.
Now, the moment you eat that food, you discover that the content is rotten.
How would you feel?
Disappointed and terrible.
No matter how beautiful the food looks, no matter how wonderfully it is presented,
if the content is not the same as the presentation, is disgusting, is rotten,
then the food is worthless.
Would you agree with me?
Such is the case of someone who values only the flesh, the appearance, the material possessions,
and neglects his heart.
Take care of your heart.
Let me try to use an example in relation to those of us here in the church today.
Remember, you are what is in your heart.
I am what is in my heart.
My life reflects what is in my heart.
So many people come to church today and their reason, their basis of coming to church
is because they want something from God.
Perhaps they want a miracle, healing, deliverance, breakthrough in their business,
prosperity, abundance - just name it.
They have come because of what they want from God.
But remember what Prophet T.B. Joshua said:
The heart is a landing point.
If there is an obstacle or an obstruction, God cannot land with His cargo of blessings.
Let's try and picture this.
By the grace of God, I know many of us have been privileged to travel by aircraft - we have flown.
Many of us even flew here.
Just imagine when you are coming in to land on your aircraft;
you look out - if you see the tarmac, where the plane is going to land,
you will see that everything is clear.
No obstruction, no obstacle, no hindrance - because if there is an obstacle at the point of landing,
the plane cannot successfully land.
Would you agree with me?
Can I have one chair please?
One chair.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Thank you.
I just want you to picture this, so you can understand what's happening when we come to church
seeking a miracle without taking care of our hearts.
This is the landing point.
This is the tarmac.
This is the area where the plane wants to land, but there is an obstacle,
there is a hindrance, there is a barrier!
No matter how fervently you pray, how passionately you worship, how you fast;
you do all night vigil - so far as the obstacle is still there, the plane cannot land.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Many of us start running from one place to another, trying to find solution,
not knowing that the problem is within us.
We have not removed the obstacle!
There is still an obstruction!
There is still something blocking us!
And we are busy going to this church, that church, this crusade, that crusade...
Before you know it, you get anointed water here, anointed oil here,
anointed pyjama here, anointed underwear here.
What other anointing do you want?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You run from man of God to man of God, but the problem is within you.
There is an obstacle!
And you know what happens?
This is the painful part.
By the time you run up and down, look for solution and you don't seem to see that blessing coming,
you hear the noise of the plane going over you and missing you -
someone else is receiving a blessing, someone else is receiving a touch
and you say, "Why not me?"
You begin to look at God in a bad light.
Perhaps He doesn't love me, perhaps He loves this person more than me,
perhaps my sin is too much that He cannot forgive.
And what happens when you look at God in a bad light and frustration and desperation comes?
Before you know it, you will find yourself being deceived.
Let me have another chair.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Just imagine; you, that are looking to remove the obstacle,
by the time, in that frustration, desperation someone says, "Let's go here".
You go there and you find yourself in the house of a spiritualist,
where you are touched by someone who is not supposed to touch you,
where you taste what a Christian is not supposed to taste.
Rather than removing the obstacle, you only seem to increase it.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
It only seems to be getting worse!
Then what happens?
You begin to look for imaginary enemies.
"That my aunt cursed me when I was young. She is the cause.
That my grandmother - oh God; God will deal with her."
What happens? What's going on?
As a result of that - another obstacle!
Oh my God!
Another one!
You begin to say, "That my business partner duped me; he is the cause.
God will punish him. God will deal with him."
When you sit back in your setback, you wallow in your self-pity - what happens?
You begin to try and create happiness outside of God, "Let me just take some alcohol".
As you take the alcohol - what happens?
Another one!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
And you want the plane to land?
You want God to come with His cargo of blessings; peace, joy, abundance, all the promises in the Scriptures,
you want them to be released unto your life, but your heart is filled with obstacles.
This is offence; you have not forgiven that person that offended you last year,
and you are here in the church today, "God, bless me. God, heal me. God, deliver me. God, set me free."
Remove offence and the blessing will come.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
What am I trying to say brethren?
When you take care of your heart, God will take care of your miracle.
When you take care of your heart, God will take care of your blessing.
When you take care of your heart, God will take care of your success.
Stop looking for imaginary enemies around you and start looking within.
Tell your neighbour; say, "Neighbour,
take care of your heart; God will take care of your blessing".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
By the time you take care of your heart and the obstacles are removed,
there’s free access for the Spirit of God to land and release unto you the abundance of His provision.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If you look at what is happening in the society today,
you will realise that it is common for people to value their material possessions above their heart.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
This is contrary to what the Scriptures teach us.
In the Word of God we realise that the Word of God, a Spirit, creates material things -
proving that the spirit is greater than material.
Why then do we place value more on our material possessions, than our hearts?
When Job 1:21 says,
“Naked I came from my mother’s womb and naked shall I return.”
What are you fighting over today, what are you squabbling, struggling, striving over today?
Your property, position, possession, what people say about you, how people look at you...
Your concern is so much about today - you are not going to carry it to the grave.
The Spirit returns to God who gave it and the flesh returns to the dust.
Ecclesiastes 12:7
The urge to store up treasures here on earth
is the cause of killing, stealing, destruction and corruption today
but how much of those things will you carry with you to eternity?
Vanity upon vanity - all is...
Why can't we take care of our hearts?
You know, it's a practical thing; physically to have a healthy body.
You don't take what you know is poisonous.
You are told that this food, ingredients is poisonous,
if you take it, you are going to fall sick, perhaps even die.
Why would anyone take something that they know is poisonous, destructive, corruptive?
To have a healthy body, you don't take what you know is poisonous.
To have a healthy heart, don’t feed on offence.
Don’t feed on bitterness, resentment or bad feelings towards anyone.
I'm not saying they will not come.
In this world there will be trouble, test, offence - they will come,
but don't harbour them in your hearts.
Don't create room for them in your hearts.
Your heart is too precious to just give to the fruits of the flesh.
Your heart is too valuable to just give to the things of the world.
Whenever you are cheated, pause and consider your conscience.
Someone cheats you, embarrasses you, insults you;
don't just retaliate, respond, react.
Pause! Consider your conscience.
My heart is too valuable to start fighting flesh and blood; I leave the battle for God.
My heart is too precious to start exchanging words with flesh and blood; I leave the issue for God.
Because your response determines your future.
Read the Book of Ephesians 4:30-32.
The Holy Spirit cannot share with a heart full of offence, unforgiveness and pain of the past.
He can't come, He can't land to release His blessings, peace, abundance of His promises,
if your heart is still full of offence.
Why can’t you let go, leave the issue with God and take care of what matters?
The secret place is a sacred place.
Anytime you have an appointment for your possessions,
remember the Creator of your possessions.
Anytime you have an appointment for your possessions, position, wealth, money, business,
remember the Creator, who is not one of those things - He is the only thing, the only reason.
Some think they have everything when money comes their way; wealth,
but that they are poor would be revealed on God's accounting day.
The rich may seem to prosper now; the wicked may seem to prosper now and live without a care -
they will spend eternity in terror and despair.
Why would we now use material possessions as a yardstick to measure our relationship with God?
I remember several years ago, and I'm sure you are aware of this...
Several years ago there was an article that was written on the internet, it was circulated and spread;
social media continued to spread this article saying, "These are the richest men of God.
They have x-amounts of money, x-amounts of this... Richest men of God".
That article was spread everywhere.
They even included the name of our father in the Lord, Prophet T.B. Joshua.
But I want to tell you one thing, and you know this as well,
because you've studied the lifestyle of Prophet T.B. Joshua.
Whether today he has 5 dollars or 5 billion dollars, you will not see any difference in him.
You will not see any change,
because this ministry of the Holy Spirit is not about making money; it’s about saving souls.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
How can we begin to use material possessions as a yardstick to measure success?
Do you know that the true measure of spiritual enrichment is contentment -
peace that surpasses all understanding, peace in the midst of the storm
and joy in the midst of the troubles.
Contentment – I am what God says I am, I have what God says I have
and I can do what God says I can do.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Contentment - that is the dividend of your relationship with God.
The Spirit is greater than the material.
Why can't we take care of our hearts, clean our hearts?
The management of our hearts and its thoughts is fundamental to our faith and holy living.
Fundamental.
It is not just trivial, something you just take by the side - it's fundamental to take care of your hearts.
Look inward.
The heart connects us to Jesus, to Him - it's all about the heart.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Once you can control your heart, you control your life.
You can get your heart to your side, temptation may come -
you quickly rebuke and reject those doubts, fears.
Refuse to take counsel with fear; refuse to entertain doubt.
Doubts must be refused and resolutely resisted.
Take captive your thoughts in obedience to Christ.
They will come.
Thoughts may come and persist in staying but you refuse to put them into words
and so they die unborn.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Brethren, to take care of your heart, your heart must be tuned to God’s Word.
Tuned, in harmony with the Word of God.
If you make God your heart’s delight, you will surely have your heart’s desires.
In conclusion:
you must balance your life.
Tell your neighbour, "Balance your life".
Anytime you nourish your physical body with natural food,
remember to nourish your soul with spiritual food.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Anytime you look in the mirror, check your appearance, clothes, dressing - that is fine;
remember to check the state of your heart.
The mirror only reveals the shell; the true me lies in the heart.
Don't let the mirror deceive you.
Anytime you take a shower, clean yourself in the morning, remove any dirt, anything in your body;
remember to clean your heart.
Is your heart free from care, worry, anxiety, offence?
These are poisonous to your spirit, heart, and block you from receiving God's blessings.
Anytime you go out in the morning to fend for your family, to work for your daily bread, earn a living -
it's good; I'm not trying to tell you you can't do that - you must, of course.
Take care of your spiritual life because that is the engine that carries your success.
You can have a beautiful car, the latest model, the most fantasticly presented -
if there is no engine, can the car work?
Why would you be so consumed by painting the car, getting the latest design, and there is no engine,
or the engine is broken?
Take care of your heart, the ‘man himself’ – the real you, the true you.
You can be emotionally or physically stressed,
but please, please, do not be spiritually stressed.
Because if you are, you would lose focus on God.
Focusing on you may lead to stress but focusing on God leads to rest.
When you become God-minded, Word-minded, the Word of God dominates your heart -
your heart will unconsciously go to Him for guidance, wisdom, strength, provision, protection.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
May God bless His Word in the midst of our hearts, in Jesus’ name.
TT ROBERT BEGIER 07/11/2018
RV: Mel Flowers 17/11/2018